Age 26

Email

salehibrian@gmail.

Phone

+98 903 121 8938

Website

briansalehi.ir

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/
briansalehi

Github

github.com/
briansalehi

Address

No 15, Mojdeh st., Pasdaran st., Tehran, Iran

Brian Salehi

Software Engineer

Professional Summary I am a Linux system programmer, having experience in C and C++ programming and using a few scripting languages and development tools. I am interested in open source movement, and I usually spend some of my spare time making open source tools or contributing to open source projects.

Fields of Expertise

Linux System Programming

Linux applications and services

User Interface Development

Designing desktop user interface using Qt framework

Fields of Studies

Linux Kernel Programming

Linux Kernel and device driver development

Image Processing

Using OpenCV library to process images and videos

Graphics Programming

Creating 3D graphics scene using OpenGL APIs

Age 26

Email

salehibrian@gmail.

Phone

+98 903 121 8938

Website

briansalehi.ir

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/ briansalehi

Github

github.com/
briansalehi

Address

No 15, Mojdeh st., Pasdaran st., Tehran, Iran

Experiences

Arad Company

aradtechs.com 05/2021 - 05/2022

Software Engineer 05/2021 - 05/2022 Contributed to user interfaces, desktop applications, 3D graphical applications, and web services of major projects.

https://aparat.com/v/7iq4Y

Training milextone.ir

Software Engineer, Technical Trainer

03/2019 - 03/2021

I had 11 bachelor's, master's and PhD level students in Iran, Germany, Poland and United States, teaching programming and administration.

Manzoomeh Negaran Holdings

seller.ir

Software Engineer, Database Specialist

06/2016 - 06/2017

Developed the back-end service and database of an industrial webstore.

Cooperations

Bioengineering Laboratory

Poland (undisclosed)

Software Engineer

08/2020 - present

Consulting technical solutions for development of computational services.

Sarmad Business Services Company

Iran (*sarmadbs.com*)

System Administrator, Database Specialist

04/2021 - 06/2021

Consulting technical solutions to maintain systems and services.

Contributions

Open source contributions will be listed here as soon as they are accepted by open source communities.

Age 26

Email

salehibrian@gmail.

Phone

+98 903 121 8938

Website

briansalehi.ir

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/ briansalehi

Github

github.com/
briansalehi

Address

No 15, Mojdeh st., Pasdaran st., Tehran, Iran

Skills

Technical Skills

C++

Writing programs using STL and Boost with recent language standards

C

Linux interface programming and developing high performance services

Python

Advanced scripting, prototyping, and automating with unit tests

x86 64 Assembly

Writing processor specific high performance procedures and data vectorization

Bash

Advanced scripting, prototyping and automating in Linux systems

Linux Administration

Configuring, automating, administering and securing Linux systems

Qt, QML

Developing full-featured cross-platform graphical user interfaces

OpenCV

Developing image and video processing applications

OpenGL, GLSL

3D graphics programming and developing game engines

PostgreSQL, MySQL, MongoDB

Designing, developing and administering relational and non-relational databases

Tools

Git

Using source control professionally along many of development workflows

Docker, Kubernetes

Dockerizing and shipping projects using advanced containarization techniques

GCC, GDB

Using compiling optimizations and debugging techniques

Sanitizers, Valgrind Suite

Using advanced profiling tools along development

Make, CMake Suite

Adapting projects to auto-compiling, testing, packaging and monitoring

Doxygen, Sphinx, UML, PlantUML

Writing precise documentations containing UML diagrams

Miscellaneous Skills

Vim

My default text editor for coding and configuring

LaTeX

Writing documents, including this resume

Age 26

Email

salehibrian@gmail.

Phone

+98 903 121 8938

Website

briansalehi.ir

LinkedIn

linkedin.com/in/ briansalehi

Github

github.com/
briansalehi

Address

No 15, Mojdeh st., Pasdaran st., Tehran, Iran

Education

Islamic Azad University, Tehran North

MSc. of Computer Science, Software Engineering 09/2021 - 06/2023

Islamic Azad University, Tehran East

iauet.ac.ir

BSc. of Computer Science

09/2016 - 06/2021

Certificates

Fanavaran Anisa Ins. anisa.co.ir

Embedded Linux 5/2021 - present

Fanavaran Anisa Ins. anisa.co.ir

Linux Application Development 5/2021 - present

Fanavaran Anisa Ins.

anisa.co.ir

LPIC-3: Linux Security 3/2017 - present

Fanavaran Anisa Ins. anisa.co.ir LPIC-2: Linux Networks 3/2016 - present

Fanavaran Anisa Ins. anisa.co.ir

LPIC-1: Linux Systems 3/2015 - present

Interests

Technical

Kernel hacking, embedded Linux, graphics programming, user interfaces, image processing, machine learning, software and hardware design, algorithms, mathematics, quantum mechanics, philosophy, psychiatry

Personal

Playing electric guitar, reading books, swimming, biking, running, hiking

Languages

English Fluent

I have a strong studying background in English.

German Basic

I'm currently learning German to the extent of communicating fluently.

References

Dr. Farhang Jaryani

fjayani@yahoo.com

Faculty of Computer Science, Arak University, Iran